Four friends have made a mistake that will change their lives forever.
Sleepers is a crime, drama, thriller film directed by Barry Levinson.
Two gangsters seek revenge on the state jail worker who during
their stay at a youth prison sexually abused them.
A sensational court hearing takes place to charge him for the crimes.
Sean Nokes, played by Kevin Bacon.
Father Bobby, played by Robert De Niro.
Danny Snyder, played by Dustin Hoffman.
Lorenzo 'Shakes' Carcaterra, played by Jason Patric.
Michael Sullivan, played by Brad Pitt.
Young Michael Sullivan, played by Brad Renfro.
Sleepers is a 1996 American legal crime drama film written, produced and directed by Barry
Levinson, and based on Lorenzo Carcaterra's 1995 book of the same name.
The film stars an ensemble cast including Kevin Bacon, Jason Patric, Brad Pitt, Robert De Niro, Dustin Hoffman, Minnie Driver, Vittorio Gassman, Brad Renfro,
Ron Eldard, Jeffrey Donovan, Terry Kinney, Joe Perrino, Geoffrey Wigdor, Jonathan Tucker, Bruno Kirby, and Billy Crudup in his film debut.
The title is an American slang term for juvenile delinquents
who serve sentences longer than nine months.
Sleepers was theatrically released on October 18, 1996 by Warner Bros.
in the United States, with PolyGram Filmed
Entertainment releasing in other territories.
The film received positive reviews from critics and was a box-office
hit, grossing $165.6 million against a $44 million budget.
The film explores themes of child abuse, sexual
abuse, court case, court, repayment.
The tone is emotional and intense.